import { QuestionType, SubjectCode } from "./utils";

const subject_code = SubjectCode.BOOK_KEEPING;
export const Bookkeeping: QuestionType[] = [
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "What is the primary purpose of bookkeeping in business?",
    option_a: "Advertising",
    option_b: "Record-keeping",
    option_c: "Market research",
    option_d: "Customer service",
    correct_option: "Record-keeping",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "In double-entry bookkeeping, every transaction affects at least how many accounts?",
    option_a: "One",
    option_b: "Two",
    option_c: "Three",
    option_d: "Four",
    correct_option: "Two",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the financial statement that shows a company's revenues and expenses over a specific period?",
    option_a: "Balance Sheet",
    option_b: "Income Statement",
    option_c: "Cash Flow Statement",
    option_d: "Statement of Retained Earnings",
    correct_option: "Income Statement",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which of the following is an example of an operating expense?",
    option_a: "Purchase of equipment",
    option_b: "Rent",
    option_c: "Loan repayment",
    option_d: "Dividend payment",
    correct_option: "Rent",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the accounting principle that assumes a business will continue operating indefinitely?",
    option_a: "Matching Principle",
    option_b: "Going Concern Principle",
    option_c: "Cost Principle",
    option_d: "Revenue Recognition Principle",
    correct_option: "Going Concern Principle",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the process of recording financial transactions in chronological order?",
    option_a: "Ledger",
    option_b: "Journal",
    option_c: "Trial Balance",
    option_d: "Income Statement",
    correct_option: "Journal",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which accounting equation represents the fundamental relationship between assets, liabilities, and equity?",
    option_a: "Assets = Liabilities",
    option_b: "Assets = Liabilities + Equity",
    option_c: "Assets = Expenses + Revenue",
    option_d: "Assets = Income - Expenses",
    correct_option: "Assets = Liabilities + Equity",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What type of account increases with a debit and decreases with a credit in double-entry bookkeeping?",
    option_a: "Revenue",
    option_b: "Liability",
    option_c: "Asset",
    option_d: "Expense",
    correct_option: "Asset",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the process of systematically allocating the cost of an asset over its useful life?",
    option_a: "Depreciation",
    option_b: "Amortization",
    option_c: "Appreciation",
    option_d: "Accrual",
    correct_option: "Depreciation",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "In bookkeeping, what is the purpose of a trial balance?",
    option_a: "To record daily transactions",
    option_b: "To prepare financial statements",
    option_c: "To verify the equality of debits and credits",
    option_d: "To calculate taxes",
    correct_option: "To verify the equality of debits and credits",
    subject_code,
  },
];
